Register of the Nym Wales papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CHINESE INDUSTRIAL COOPERATIVES, 1936-1950, 1958 (Boxes 1-9)
  - Collected writings and speeches, 1938-1942 (Boxes 3-4)
    - Smythe, Lewis, 1939-1942
      - "A Letter from China (June 25, 1939)," Manila World, printed copy, 1939 August 8 (Box-folder 4: 33)
      - "Every Co-op A Nucleus of a New World in the Making," World Call, printed copy, 1941 April (Box-folder 4: 34)
      - "The Chinese Industrial Cooperative Movement," China at War, printed copy, 1942 October (Box-folder 4: 35)
    - Snow, Edgar, 1938-1940, undated
      - Articles, 1939-1940, undated
        - "China's New Industrial Army," Manila World, printed copy and carbon copy of typescript, 1939 October 10 (Box-folder 4: 36)
        - "The Dragon Licks His Wounds," Saturday Evening Post, printed copy and carbon copy of typescript draft, 1940 April 13 (Box-folder 4: 37)
        - "China's Blitzbuilder, Rewi Alley," Saturday Evening Post, reprint, undated (Box-folder 4: 38)
      - Reports, circa 1939-1940, undated
        - "Discussion of Needs of Partisan Districts in Japanese Rear for Immediate Military Supplies and for Establishment of Small Mobile War Industries," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 4: 39)
        - "Recommendations to the International Committee," typescript with carbon copies, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 4: 40)
      - Speeches, undated
        - "War and Change in China," carbon copy of typewritten transcript, undated (Box-folder 4: 41)
      - News dispatches sent to the London Daily Herald, carbon copy of typescript, 1938 September 20 (Box-folder 4: 42)
      - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box-folder 4: 43)
    - Sun, Madame Yat-Sen, 1939
      - "Towards the achievement of Chinese Independence," Manila World, printed copies, 1939 November 22-23 (Box-folder 4: 44)
      - Transcript of radio broadcast on Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, 1939 December (Box-folder 4: 45)
    - Tayler, J. B., 1937-1938
      - "Cooperative Industrial Policy for China in the Present Emergency," carbon copy of typescript, 1938 May 2 (Box-folder 4: 46)
      - "Potentialities of the Cooperative Movement in China," Chinese Social and Political Science Review, printed copy, 1937 April (Box-folder 4: 47)
    - Tseng, Li-Kwang. "New Hope for China," Threshold, printed copy, 1942 October (Box-folder 4: 48)
    - Walsh, Richard J. "China Cooperates," Manila World, printed copy and typescript, 1939 August 1 (Box-folder 4: 49)
    - Wang, Mei-tseng, "The Conditions of the Progress in Industry of the Shensi-Kansu-Ninghsia Border Region,", 1941 November (Box-folder 4: 50)
      Includes a transcript of the article published in Liberation Daily.
    - Willcox, Helen L. One for All, carbon copy of script for one-act play, undated (Box-folder 4: 51)
    - Vey, Ruth, "Cooperatives in the Northwest," China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1940 May 4 (Box-folder 4: 52)
  - Collected correspondence, 1938-1950 (Boxes 5-6)
    Contains correspondence of organizations and individuals associated with the Chinese Industrial Cooperative movement.
    - General correspondence, 1938-1950
      - Alley, Rewi, 1938-1943 (Box-folder 5: 1)
      - American Friends Service Committee, 1950 (Box-folder 5: 2)
      - Baker, John Earl, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 3)
      - Barker, Alfred F., 1944 (Box-folder 5: 4)
      - Carlson, Evans F., 1940 (Box-folder 5: 5)
      - Carter, Edward C., 1939, 1942 (Box-folder 5: 6)
      - Chen, Dalton, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 7)
      - Chen, Han-seng, 1939-1940, 1942 (Box-folder 5: 8)
      - Chinese Engineering Students Association of the University of the Philippines, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 9)
      - Chinese Red Cross, 1939 (Box-folder 5: 10)
      - Chuan, Mrs. Dee C., Philippine Chinese Women's Relief Association, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 11)
      - Donald, W. H., 1939 (Box-folder 5: 12)
      - Edwards, Dwight (United China Relief), 1943-1944 (Box-folder 5: 13)
      - Fitch, George A., 1940-1941 (Box-folder 5: 14)
      - Fitch, Geraldine, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 15)
      - Foley, Walter B., 1940 (Box-folder 5: 16)
      - Freeman, Mansfield, 1944 (Box-folder 5: 17)
      - Gunther, John, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 18)
      - Herman, Theodore, 1940, 1947 (Box-folder 5: 19)
      - Hogg, George Aylwin, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 20)
      - Lanchow Bailie School, 1947 (Box-folder 5: 21)
      - Lapwood, E. Ralph, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 5: 22)
      - Lem, F. Y., 1938, 1941 (Box-folder 5: 23)
      - Liang, Hubert S., 1940 (Box-folder 5: 24)
      - Liu, Kwang Pei, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 5: 25)
      - Loomis, Helen, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 5: 26)
      - Los Angeles-Hollywood Organizing Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, 1941 (Box-folder 5: 27)
      - Lu, Kwang Mein, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 5: 28)
      - Mei, Y. P., 1940 (Box-folder 5: 29)
      - Meng, Sho-tseng, 1941 (Box-folder 5: 30)
      - Meng, Yung-chien, 1941 (Box-folder 5: 31)
      - More, G. R. (American Red Cross), 1944 (Box-folder 5: 32)
      - Northwest Education Planning Committee, 1938 (Box-folder 5: 33)
      - Price, Mildred (China Aid Council), 1940 (Box-folder 5: 34)
      - Pruitt, Ida (American Committee for Chinese Industrial Cooperatives), 1939-1940 (Box-folder 5: 35)
      - Reisner, John H., 1940 (Box-folder 5: 36)
      - Robinson, Leland Rex (American Bureau for Aid to China), 1942 (Box-folder 5: 37)
      - Sa, Chien-li, 1939 (Box-folder 5: 38)
      - Shen, Reggie, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 5: 39)
      - Smythe, Lewis and Margaret, 1939-1945 (Box-folder 5: 40)
      - Sun, Madame Yat-Sen (Soong Ching Ling), 1942-1944 (Box-folder 5: 41)
      - Sweet, Lennig, United China Relief, 1944 (Box-folder 5: 42)
      - Taft, Charles A. (President's War Relief Control Board), 1942 (Box-folder 5: 43)
      - Tan, C. K., 1939 (Box-folder 5: 44)
      - Tayler, J. B., 1938-1939 (Box-folder 5: 45)
      - Van Slyke, Dr. Donald D., 1944 (Box-folder 5: 46)
      - Webber, John W., 1940 (Box-folder 5: 47)
      - Wong, Y. Lang, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 5: 48)
      - Yarnell, Admiral Harry E., 1940 (Box-folder 5: 49)
      - Yeh, Ruth Weiss, 1944 (Box-folder 5: 50)
      - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1938-1944 (Box-folder 5: 51)
    - Indusco, Inc. American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, 1942-1950
      - General, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 6: 1)
        Includes correspondence to members of the board of directors.
      - Alley, Rewi, 1942-1948 (Box-folder 6: 2)
      - Babcock, Polly (Mrs. W. R.), 1941 (Box-folder 6: 3)
      - Bickerton, Max, 1947 (Box-folder 6: 4)
      - Campbell, Mal, 1947 (Box-folder 6: 5)
      - Carlson, Evans F., 1941 (Box-folder 6: 6)
      - Carpenter, J. Henry, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 7)
      - Carter, Edward C., 1942, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 6: 8)
      - Chang, Kuan Lien, 1945 (Box-folder 6: 9)
      - Chiang, Kai-shek, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 10)
      - Chen, Han-seng, 1942, 1944 (Box-folder 6: 11)
      - Currie, Lauchlin, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 12)
      - Curtis, Francis, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 13)
      - Edison, Charles, 1945 (Box-folder 6: 14)
      - Fairfax-Cholmeley, Elsie, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 6: 15)
      - Ferguson, Mary (United China Relief), 1944 (Box-folder 6: 16)
      - Fisher, Welthy, 1947 (Box-folder 6: 17)
      - Fitch, George A., 1942 (Box-folder 6: 18)
      - Foley, William E. (U.S. Department of Justice), 1950 (Box-folder 6: 19)
      - Foster, John B., 1942 (Box-folder 6: 20)
      - Fox, A. Manuel, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 21)
      - Fox, Melvin J., 1949 (Box-folder 6: 22)
      - Freeman, Mansfield (United China Relief), 1945 (Box-folder 6: 23)
      - Garside, B. A. (United China Relief), 1944 (Box-folder 6: 24)
      - Glass, Muriel, 1943 (Box-folder 6: 25)
      - Hall, Ronald O. (Episcopal Bishop of Hong Kong), 1942-1949 (Box-folder 6: 26)
      - Herman, Theodore, 1947 (Box-folder 6: 27)
      - Herod, W. R. (United China Relief), 1942 (Box-folder 6: 28)
      - Hogg, George Aylwin, 1942, 1944 (Box-folder 6: 29)
      - Illesley, Walter, 1949 (Box-folder 6: 30)
      - Kemp, Donald, 1950 (Box-folder 6: 31)
      - Kennedy, Mary, 1947 (Box-folder 6: 32)
      - Kung, H. H., 1944 (Box-folder 6: 33)
      - Lapwood, E. Ralph, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 6: 34)
      - McConaughty, Dr. James L., 1944 (Box-folder 6: 35)
      - Meng, S. T., 1949 (Box-folder 6: 36)
      - Meng, Yung-chien, 1942, 1949 (Box-folder 6: 37)
      - Morrison, Colin, 1948 (Box-folder 6: 38)
      - Perry, Henry G., 1944 (Box-folder 6: 39)
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Mrs. Franklin D.), 1942 (Box-folder 6: 40)
      - Sayre, Elizabeth, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 41)
      - Smythe, Lewis, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 6: 42)
      - Soong, T. V., 1942, 1945 (Box-folder 6: 43)
      - Tan, J. M., 1944 (Box-folder 6: 44)
      - Tayler, J. B., 1943 (Box-folder 6: 45)
      - Tee-Van, Mrs. (United China Relief), 1945 (Box-folder 6: 46)
      - Townsend, Peter, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 6: 47)
      - Van Slyke, Dr. Donald D., 1944 (Box-folder 6: 48)
      - Veatch, Roy, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 49)
      - Walsh, Richard J., 1941 (Box-folder 6: 50)
      - Welles, Sumner (Acting Secretary of State), 1942 (Box-folder 6: 51)
      - Wong, Y. Lang, 1945 (Box-folder 6: 52)
      - Woodman, Dorothy (Anglo-Chinese Development Society), 1945 (Box-folder 6: 53)
      - Miscellaneous, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 6: 54)
    - Philippine Association for Industrial Cooperatives in China, 1939-1941
      - Alley, Rewi, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 55)
      - Chen, Mr., 1940 (Box-folder 6: 56)
      - Chiang, Madame Kai-shek, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 57)
      - Chiang, Shu-huan (Mrs. K. M. Lu), 1940 (Box-folder 6: 58)
      - Hall, Ronald O. (Episcopal Bishop of Hong Kong), 1940 (Box-folder 6: 59)
      - Hogg, George Aylwin, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 60)
      - Hoover, Herbert, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 61)
        Contains an appeal concerning China relief.
      - Jen, Chu-min, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 62)
      - International Committee of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 63)
      - Kho, Chong-su, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 64)
      - Kung, H. H., undated (Box-folder 6: 65)
      - Liu, Kwang Pei, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 66)
      - Lu, Kwang Mein, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 67)
      - Luce, Henry, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 68)
      - McNutt, Mrs. Paul V., 1939-1940 (Box-folder 6: 69)
      - Philippine Chinese Women's Relief Association, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 70)
      - Roys, Mrs. Charles Kirkland (Church Committee for China Relief), 1940 (Box-folder 6: 71)
      - Shih, Fan, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 72)
      - Soong, T. V., 1939 (Box-folder 6: 73)
      - Sun, Te Liang, 1941 (Box-folder 6: 74)
      - Women's Work Department of the Chinese Industrial Cooperative Northwest Headquarters, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 75)
      - Wong, Lang, 1940 (Box-folder 6: 76)
      - Yarnell, Admiral Harry E., 1940 (Box-folder 6: 77)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 6: 78)
  - Collected records of the Chinese Industrial Cooperative movement, 1930s-1940s (Boxes 7-9)
    - Anglo-Chinese (Cooperative) Development Society, undated (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Central Promotion Committee, undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - Chinese Industrial Cooperative Associations (Societies), undated
      - General (Box-folder 7: 3)
      - Che-wan Regional Headquarters, Chekiang Office (Box-folder 7: 4)
      - Che-wan Regional Headquarters, Anhwei Office (Box-folder 7: 5)
      - Chin-yu Regional Headquarters, Southeast Shansi Depot (Box-folder 7: 6)
      - Chuan-kong Regional Headquarters, Chengtu Office, undated (Box-folder 7: 7)
      - Chuan-kong Regional Headquarters, Yung Chang Depot (Box-folder 7: 8)
      - Northwest Regional Headquarters (Shensi, Chainghai, Kansu, Ninghsia), undated
        - General (Box-folder 7: 9)
        - Lanchow Office (Box-folder 7: 10)
        - Nancheng Office (Box-folder 7: 11)
        - Shensi-Kansu-Ninghsia Border District (Box-folder 7: 12)
        - Shuangshipu Hospital (Box-folder 7: 13)
        - Tienshui Office (Box-folder 7: 14)
        - Yennan Office (Box-folder 7: 15)
      - Southeast Regional Headquarters (Box-folder 7: 16-17)
      - Yunnan Regional Headquarters (Box-folder 7: 18)
    - Hong Kong (Shanghai) Promotion Committee, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - Indusco, Inc., American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 8: 2-3)
      Also known as the American Committee for Chinese Industrial Cooperatives.
    - Industrial Cooperative Commission, undated (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - Industrial Cooperative Institute, undated (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - Industrial Cooperative Trust of China, undated (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - Institute for the Advancement of Indusco, undated (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - International Committee for Chinese Industrial Cooperatives Productive Relief Fund, undated (Box-folder 8: 8)
    - Organizing Committee, 1938 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    - Philippine Association for Industrial Cooperatives in China, undated (Box-folder 8: 10)
    - United China Relief, undated (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Handbills, advertisements, and posters of various Chinese Industrial Cooperative Associations, undated (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Biographical material, undated (Box 9)
    - Alley, Rewi (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - Lem, Frank (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Liang, Hubert S. (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Pruitt, Ida (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - News clippings, 1938-1941, undated (Box 9)
    - 1938 (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - 1939 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - 1940 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - 1941 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - Undated (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Miscellaneous printed and typewritten material, undated (Box-folder 9: 11)
- CHINESE LABOR MOVEMENT, 1934-1945, undated (Box 10)
  Writings, speeches, articles, and news agency releases related to the history of the Chinese labor movement from the 1920s to the mid 1940s.
  - Chronologies of the Chinese labor movement, undated (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Writings and speeches, circa 1945
    Writing and speeches by Nym Wales arranged by literary form and then chronologically.
    - Articles and essays, 1945, undated
      - "The Chinese Labor Movement," carbon copies of typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 10: 2)
      - "Chinese Labor and War Production," typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 10: 3)
      - "Labor Unions in China," The Protestant, typescript draft and printed copy, 1945 May (Box-folder 10: 4)
      - "The Fate of Labor under Chiang," The Protestant, typescript draft and printed copy, 1945 August-September (Box-folder 10: 5)
        The typescript draft has a different title.
    - Books, 1945
      - The Chinese Labor Movement (Box-folder 10: 6-8)
        Contains chapter drafts and notes.
    - Speeches and interviews, undated
      - Notes for a talk on the Chinese Labor Movement, typescript (Box-folder 10: 9)
      - Interview discussing The Chinese Labor Movement, carbon copy of typewritten transcript (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Collected writings, 1934-1944, undated
    Arranged alphabetically by author or title.
    - "Background of the Chinese Labor Movement," carbon copy of typescript, 1942 April (Box-folder 10: 11)
    - Chu, Hseuh-fan, "Memoranda of the Problem of Chinese Seamen on European Ships," mimeograph, 1942 April (Box-folder 10: 12)
    - "Zhongguo de baogong zhi," manuscript, 1934 (Box-folder 10: 13)
      English translation of title: "Chinese Contract Working System
    - "Yijiusansi nian baiqu gongren douzheng tongji," carbon copy of handwritten manuscript, 1934 (Box-folder 10: 14)
      See also: Oversize Material, number 1.
    - "A Labor Hero in Yenan," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 10: 15)
    - "Labor Movement in North China," typescript, 1944 July (Box-folder 10: 16)
    - "Labor Trouble at the Bureau of Printing and Engraving in Peiping," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 10: 17)
    - Lowe, Chuan-Hua, "Facing Labor Issues in China," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 10: 18)
    - "Memorandum on conversation with Ernest Liu," carbon copy of typescript, 1942 May 8 (Box-folder 10: 19)
    - Mu, Yi, "Labor Policy and Workers' Life in the Border Regions," carbon copy of typescript, 1942 October 20 (Box-folder 10: 20)
    - "ShangHai RenLiChe FengChao," carbon copy of manuscript, 1934 (Box-folder 10: 21)
      English translation of title: "The Shanghai Rickshaw Workers Strike"
    - "Shanghai Ying Mei Yan GongSi TongMeng BaGong," carbon copy of manuscript, 1934 (Box-folder 10: 22)
      English translation of title: "Shanghai British-American Tobacco Company Strike"
    - Tang, H. "Beginnings of Industry," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 10: 23)
    - "The Workers Struggle of the Bureau of Printing and Engraving in Peiping," typescript, undated (Box-folder 10: 24)
  - Magazine and journal articles, undated (Box-folder 10: 25)
  - Allied Labor News news releases, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 10: 26)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 10: 27)
- CHINESE STUDENT MOVEMENT, 1931-1937, 1959 (Boxes 11-14)
  Correspondence, writings, news agency releases, news clippings, broadsides, and manifestos related to the Chinese student movement during the 1930s and particularly the role of Nym Wales as a journalist and friend of the students. A guide to the material, prepared by Nym Wales, appears at the beginning of the series.
  - "Notes on the Chinese Student Movement, 1935-1936,", 1959 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
    Two copies of a mimeograph transcript written by Nym Wales as a guide to the following material. 201 pages total.
  - Chronologies of the Chinese student movement, undated (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Correspondence of Nym Wales and Edgar Snow, 1935-1937 (Box 11)
    - Bein, Ning-tze, 1936 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Chang, Chao-lin, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Chen, H. H., 1936 (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - Fisher, Mac, 1936 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Li, Min, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 11: 8)
      Also known as "Marie" or "Matsuhara."
    - Liu, Tsui ("Suzie"), 1935-1937 (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - Oliver, Frank, 1936 (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - Powell, J. B., 1935-1936 (Box-folder 11: 11)
    - Walsh, Richard J., 1936 (Box-folder 11: 12)
    - Wang, Ju-mei, 1936 (Box-folder 11: 13)
      Also known as Hua Huang.
    - Yang, undated (Box-folder 11: 14)
    - Yeh, Te-kuang, 1936 (Box-folder 11: 15)
    - Yui, David, 1936 (Box-folder 11: 16)
      Also known as Ch'i-wei Yu or Ching Huang.
    - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - Writings, 1935-1937 (Box 11)
    Writings by Nym Wales arranged by literary form and then chronologically.
    - Articles and essays, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 11: 18-34)
      - "Is Youth Crushed Again in China?," carbon copy of unpublished typescript draft, 1935 October (Box-folder 11: 18)
        Includes notes.
      - "Student Revival in North China," China Weekly Review, carbon copy of typescript draft, 1935 November 16 (Box-folder 11: 19)
        Author listed as Hsueh Hai-lun, Wales' Chinese pseudonym. Includes letter to J. B. Powell, editor of the China Weekly Review.
      - "The Peiping Student Movement," and "Futher Developments in the Peiping Student Movement," China Weekly Review, 1935 December 28 (Box-folder 11: 20)
        Author of the first article listed as Peggy Foster Snow, another pseudonym of Nym Wales. Articles appear on consecutive pages with photos annotated by Nym Wales. Also included are carbon copies of typescript drafts with slightly different titles.
      - "Newsmen and Student Demonstrations in Peiping," China Weekly Review, carbon copy of typescript draft and printed copy, 1935 December 28 (Box-folder 11: 21)
      - "Half-Century Sino-American Educational Development Manaced by Japanese Domination" and "The Propaganda War and Afterward," China Weekly Review, printed copies with annotated photos, 1936 February 22 (Box-folder 11: 22)
        The first article was probably written by Nym Wales; however, no author is stated. The second article is authored by "A Correspondent in Peiping," in this case, Nym Wales.
      - "On the Student Front in Peiping,", 1936
        Includes articles written for the China Weekly Review under the title "On the Student Front in Peiping" or "On the Peiping Student Front." All articles listed as being written by "A Correspondent in Peiping," in this case, Nym Wales.
        - March 7 (Box-folder 11: 23)
        - March 21 (Box-folder 11: 24)
        - April 11 (Box-folder 11: 25)
        - May 2 (Box-folder 11: 27)
        - May 23 (Box-folder 11: 28)
        - June 13 (Box-folder 11: 29)
        - June 27 (Box-folder 11: 30)
      - "The students in the north...," untitled manuscript, 1936 April 29 (Box-folder 11: 26)
        Includes letter to J. B. Powell.
      - "Scores of students...," untitled carbon copy of typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 11: 31)
      - "Liu Tsui of Tsingghua," carbon copy of typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 11: 32)
      - "China's Youth in Revolt," carbon copy of typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 11: 33)
        Authorship uncertain.
      - Miscellaneous incomplete drafts, undated (Box-folder 11: 34)
    - News dispatches, circa 1936-1937 (Box-folder 11: 35)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 11: 36-38)
      - General (Box-folder 11: 36)
      - Wang, Ju-mei (Hua Huang) (Box-folder 11: 37)
      - Yui, David (Box-folder 11: 38)
        Also known as Ch'i-wei Yu and Ching Huang.
  - Collected writings, 1936, undated (Box 12)
    - "Confession of a Blue-Shirt Member," Chiu-Kuo Shih-Pao, Paris, carbon copies typescripts, 1936 March 20 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Han, Li-sheng, "The Principle Duty of the National Salvation Movement at the Present Stage," Hseuh-sheng Hu-sheng (Student Voice Magazine), 1936 May 1 (Box-folder 12: 2)
      Typescript translation from Chinese.
    - Hsi-Hsien, "The Meaning and Duty of the Student Movement," Hseuh-sheng Hu-sheng (Student Voice Magazine), 1936 May 1 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - [Peita University student], "Since the conclusion of the anti-imperialist movement...," typescript, 1936 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - Snow, Edgar, news dispatches sent to the London Daily Herald, undated (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - [Tsinghua University student], "Of course we had been expecting a raid...," carbon copy of typescript draft, 1936 March 1 (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Tsin, "A General Survey of the Student Movement Since the December 9th (sic)," Hseuh-sheng Hu-sheng (Student Voice Magazine), 1936 May 1 (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - Wang, Ju-mei (Hua Huang), 1936, undated (Box-folder 12: 8-9)
    - Wang, Pin-tao, "The Chief Work of Students at Present," Hseuh-sheng Hu-sheng (Student Voice Magazine), 1936 May 1 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - News agency releases, circa 1935-1936 (Box 12)
    - Kuo Min News, undated (Box-folder 12: 13)
    - Reuters, undated (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - Tass Translation Service, undated (Box-folder 12: 12)
    - United Press, undated (Box-folder 12: 14)
  - News clippings from English-language Chinese press, 1931-1936, undated (Box-folder 12: 15-20)
    Arranged chronologically by year.
  - Manifestos, broadsides, resolutions and appeals, circa 1935-1936 (Boxes 13-14)
    Material in Chinese and English, issued by faculty and student associations and arranged according to the issuing organization. See also: Sino-Japanese Conflict and Oversize Material, numbers 2-7.
    - General (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - American Student Union (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Chung-kuo University, Peiping (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - Cultural Circles National Liberation Association (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Fu-tan (Fudan) University, Shanghai (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Min-kuo College, Peiping (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - National Peiping University (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - National Salvation Associations (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - National Tsinghua University (Box-folder 13: 9)
    - North China Brain-Workers Association (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - Northern China Cultural Workers Association (Box-folder 13: 11)